JOÃO PAULO CERCAL Munich, Germany

www.linkedin.com/in/jpcercal www.github.com/jpcercal

About me

I'm a ZCPE (Zend Certified PHP Engineer) familiar with agile model of software development cycle. I've been working with PHP since 2009, I'm passionate for open-source, patterns, tests and source code well written. Always looking for best practices, new technologies and methodologies to improve my workflow and bring great results to the project and to my customer.

Skills

Languages, Tools and Technologies

jQuery

Angular	■ Git	Laravel	■ PHP	TwitterBootstrap
Apache	■ Grunt	Less	PHPUnit	Vagrant
CSS	HTML	Linux	Sass	Windows
Devops	Java	MySQL	Silex	Wordpress
Docker	lavascript	Nginx	SVN	Zend

OSX

Experience

Doctrine

FlixBus Senior PHP Developer Currently

Symfony

- Changing the life of approximately one billion of people commuting, spending their weekends, building remote relationships, visiting relatives, and discovering the world;
- We improved the response time for retrieving a cart in almost 70% by extracting the code from the monolith to a new micro-service-oriented architecture;
- Volunteer to be a facilitator in agile ceremonies such as retrospective and spring review;
- Responsible for taking decisions from a technical perspective regarding our domain.

NeoGrid Senior PHP Developer 2015 - 2017

- Created a web application using Material Design and AngularJS to the front-end and Silex to the back-end, which automated the sales of the WebEDI solution;
- Implemented improvements, bug fixes and integrations with NeoGrid solutions using REST APIs;
- Added the Vagrant tool to use with my team in order to use environments identical with the production environment;
- Evangelist of best practices of programming following the existent PSRs and implementing unit test in the projects;
- Reference in my team to projects that was written in PHP and AngularJS.

Humantech PHP Developer 2015 - 2015

- Led the team (five workers) as assistant manager of the programming department when the manager was not present;
- Added unit tests in critical project parts, reducing considerable the amount of bugs and increasing the quality of projects;
- Created an e-learning platform using the gamification concepts.

A2C PHP Developer 2013 - 2014

 Created a CMS to the 3M brand using the gamification concepts and fully focused on SEO, that resulted in three times more access to the website in few months;

- Created a software to monitor the reputation of political candidates in social networks, that give more visibility on medias to the agency;
- Reference in my team to projects that was written in Symfony 2;
- Responsible to manage the Amazon Web Services EC2, RDS and S3.

Education

UNISOCIESC

BSc Information Systems

2011 - 2014

- Honor as the best student of the course;
- The final paper is based on a tool created to be used by professionals that are studying to achieve the ZCPE certification, the project is open-source and is available on GitHub, the project is hosted by "DigitalOcean" as a sponsor.